







Technical Architect/Project Manager seeking roles in Software

Development, Requirement Gathering, Functional Specifications, Net Core, ASP.net

MVC, ASP. Net, HTML, DHTML, AJAX, jQuery, JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap, Azure, ADO. Net, LINQ, Entity

Current Designation: Technical Architect, Project Manager-IT Total Experience: 15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: L&T Infotech Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Thane Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Ireland, United States (US), Switzerland
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance
Role: Tech Architect

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Technical Architect/Project Manager, Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Functional Specifications. Net Core ASP net

-MC, ASP. Net, HTML, DHTML, AJAX, jQuery, JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap, Azure, ADO. Net, LINQ, Entity, TOGAF, Enterprise-properties of the properties of the properties

Architect,

Verified : C Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section | Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Acompetent professional with nearly 15 years of experience in architecture, technical design, production support & delivery of software applications in Life Insurance, Healthcare, Internal Systems, Manufacturing domains

Experience in formulating IT strategies to improve competitive positions & business performance and achieve better business results by developing a vision and executable roadmaps that align technology and business

Expertise in analysing and modified existing codes to incorporate changes in the application / user requirements, wrote new codes as required

Updated knowledge by studying state-of-the-art development tools, programming techniques, and computing equipment, participating in educational opportunities, reading professional publications and maintaining personal networks

Delivered code changes more frequently and reliably through CI/CD Pipeline configuration

Work Experience

L&T Infotech as Technical Architect, Project Manager-IT Nov 2018 to Till Date

Title: IIOT

Period: Jan 2019 ? Till Date

Client: Post Consumer Brands (US), Airbus (Europe), Chevron (US)

Team Size: 50 Individuals including 4 Team Leads

Role: Technical Architect, Project Manager

Responsibilities:

Working as part of Scrum team and taking complete ownership for demo for completed stories, scrum planning meetings, sprint review meetings, spring retrospective meetings & release meeting

Preparing and presenting delivery status to senior management and customers

Designing web-based application using Angular, ASP.Net MC, .Net Core, ASP.NET, C#, WebAPI and database design with DFDs; implementing Business layer, Data access layer and front-end layer

Reviewing SOW and planning resources ramp up/down, allocations and deliveries accordingly

Evaluating the performance of team members and determine training needs, acting as primary contact for customer inquiries and escalations.

Managing team of 50 team members including 4 team leads: meeting business requirement gathering, task allocation, task tracking and development of application

Managing risks/issues and tracking the transition plan, adhering to norms of quality assurance and Release Delivered SIX development projects within span of 1.5 years in LTI

Worked six months at Onsite location in UK

Environment: ASP.NET MC, .Net Core, Azure, Devops C#.NET, Entity Framework, Visual Studio.NET 2017, WebAPI, SOI Sener 2014. iQuery, JavaScript Chart is Rootstran Angular Anile SCRUM CIT SonarQube

Important

Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

ا صدر المارين عن التر إعلاما إلى المارين المارين المارين المارين المارين المارين المارين المارين المارين الماري

Atos-Syntel Pvt. Ltd. as Senior Technical Leader

Sep 2014 to Nov 2018

Client: HCA (Hospital Corporation of America) All State, RSA, IS

Team Size: 20 Individuals including 2 Team Leads

Role: Senior Technical Lead

Responsibilities:

Working as part of Scrum team and taking complete ownership for demo for completed stories, scrum planning meetings, sprint review meetings, spring retrospective meetings & release meeting

Preparing and presenting delivery status to senior management and customers

Designing and developing web-based application using ASP.Net M/C, ASP.NET, C#, WebAPI and database design with DFDs; implementing Business layer, Data access layer and front-end layer

Verifying PHI policies are taken care while development of modules.

Evaluating the performance of team members and determine training needs, acting as primary contact for customer inquiries and escalations.

Managing team of 20 team members including 2 team leads: meeting business requirement gathering, task allocation, task tracking and development of application

Managing risks/issues and tracking the transition plan, adhering to norms of quality assurance and Code Release; defining SLAs for production support applications

Worked one year at Onsite location at UK

Environment: AŚP.NET M/C, C#.NET, Entity Framework, Visual Studio.NET 2017, WebAPI, SQL Server 2012, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, LINQ, Agile, SCRUM, GIT, Devops

GeBBS Healthcare Solutions as Project Leader

Oct 2011 to Sep 2014

Title: GEBBS Healthcare Solutions

Position: Project Leader

Client: US based Medical Billing Companies as well as Internal Clients

Role: Project Lead

Responsibilities:

Led client interaction, project initiation, project planning, resource management and management of team and development of DFD'S and timesheet approvals

Developed application using C# & .NET Framework 3.5, database communication using SQL Server & Oracle Processed web development using Web forms, HTML, CSS and DHTML.

Forwarded client-side validation performed with Java Script, Ajax and jQuery while compiling and deploying Test and Dev Servers

Redesigned old applications and development of new advanced alternate applications from scratch which eventually replaced old

Created and consumed WCF based services AD integration; initiated Code Review, Testing, UAT and sign-off Designed environment for software's in Gebbs which consisted of server configuration, technology selection, coding standards

Implemented Maker and Checker mechanism for various process flows along with configurable escalation matrix

Developed Advance Medical coding application for ICD/CPT auto coding and HL7 file integration with real time data
ansfer

Defined Auto QC logic. Auto Allocation. Low Level Protocol Communication; developed Document sharing platform between Client and Medical Coders

Environment

ASP.NET 3.5, C#.NET, ADO.NET, Visual Studio.NET 2013, WCF, SQL Server 2012, AJAX, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Projects

P2P [Paper to Payment] Phase 1 and 2 [23 Sub Sites], Easy Code [EC], ICODE, IERA, Provider Net, HL7 Receiver/Sender, Code Catch, Screen Scrapper, Mnerva, Buzz, IAR, Gebbs Excel Tool [GET]

Byzan Systems as Team Leader

Apr 2010 to Sep 2011

Led the management of Team and Development of DFD's and Timesheet Approvals

Initiated the preparation of HLD and LLD and Code Review

Developed application by using C# & .NET Framework 3.5, database communication using SQL Server as well as Oracle including web development using Web forms, HTML, CSS and DHTML

Designed DAL for the Byzan related projects; consumed WCF based services as well as defining the authentication modes for WCF and front-end communication; led Certificate based authentication.

Initiated Code Review, Testing, UAT and getting sign-off; consumed IRDA Web Services through secured channels and reconciling data

Processed:

- o LDAP based authentication by using Tivoli Provider
- o Development of Workflow based applications
- o Integration of .Net and Java based applications for data communication

Worked on:

- 3/N Tier applications & used messaging platform for sending SMS
- o Windows services to initiate ECS based payment and status check
- Windows services to initiate Data Transfer from Oracle legacy system to SQL Server based payment and status check

Accord Technology as Senior Software Developer

May 2006 to Mar 2010

Led the management of Team and Development of DFD's and Timesheet Approvals
Developed application by using C# & .NET Framework 1.1, 2.0, 3.0, 3.5, database communication using SQL Server as
well as Oracle including web development using Web forms, HTML, CSS and DHTML

^ Back to Top

Education

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
.Net Core, ASP.net MVC, ASP.Net		
HTML/DHTML, AJAX, jQuery, Angular		
JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap, Azure		
C#.Net, VB.Net, .Net ML		
SQL Server 2016/2012/2008/2005/2000		
Oracle 10g, MS-Access, Pi Historian		
.Net Core WebAPI, WCF, Web Services, XML		
ADO.Net, LINQ, Entity Framework, EF Core		
TFS, GIT, Visual Source Safe, SVN, Devop		
SSIS, SSRS, MS-Project, Visio, CSS, XSD		
Crystal Reports, SonarQube, JIRA		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Urdu	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Marathi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Malayalam	Beginner			✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa Countries: India,United Kingdom

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.